<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Tom Colligan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tom Colligan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.127.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/clean-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/clean-code/</guid>
      <description>clean code /klēn kōd/ • future-proofing your software
During my Master&amp;rsquo;s in Computer Science, I focused on applying code as a means to an end. My work in satellite computer vision involved extensive coursework in math and machine learning, but not necessarily software design. However, I quickly realized during a personal review process that writing complex code tends to lead to unnecessary mental overhead, increased development time, and the tendency to curse yourself a few months down the road (why did I write it like that?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/review-fy-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/review-fy-2024/</guid>
      <description>blockers from fiscal year 2024, plans for next non-exhaustive and mutable list
The cluster is down today, so I&amp;rsquo;m working on this in the meantime (as time spent reflecting can lead to massive workflow speedups).
The LPJ pipeline is starting to become a beast. It&amp;rsquo;s swelling and feels a bit unwieldy at times. I would like to transition to a true workflow management library to keep everything in pure Python. I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that when I need to write code fast the quality really deteriorates, and requires refactoring later.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/review/</guid>
      <description>personal review /ˌäptəməˈzāSH(ə)n/ • the process of examining your workflow to resolve blockers
Some years ago, I noticed that my deep learning workflows all had one thing in common: It was near impossible to reproduce every experiment I ran without a lot of work. I kept good notes but sometimes what you really need is the exact code of your experiment, plus a description. Ideally, you&amp;rsquo;d track everything on Git, but paths change, data loaders evolve, and minor tweaks like adjusting n_layers from 10 to 12 don&amp;rsquo;t always fit neatly into version control.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sse/</guid>
      <description>scientific software engineer /ˌsīənˈtifik ˈsôf(t)ˌwer ˌenjəˈnir/ • Jack of all trades, master of some
Scientific software engineers are often tasked with &amp;ldquo;making things work&amp;rdquo;. This means jumping headfirst into an unfamiliar field (biogeochemistry and biogeography from physics and computer science, for example) and using technical and formal problem-solving skills to make rapid progress. Collaboration and communication with diverse stakeholders is crucial, given the unfamiliar terrain that SSEs are exposed to from day one.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>year in review / yir in rəˈvyo͞o / • Granular account of accomplishments
FY 2025 Presented a poster on low latency biospheric carbon modeling at AGU 2024. The aforementioned poster. I was more interested in the whole biogeosciences part of the conference but submitted to a computational section. More info for next year&amp;rsquo;s AGU!
I learned quite a bit from AGU and as always came away with many interesting ideas.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
